ALI TURSUCULAR

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

alitursucular@gmail.com +44 7367 854707

Career summary

I am an accomplished Front End Web Developer and an engineer for 6+ years. I am responsible, focused, open-minded and motivated person with a great grasp of learning and team working skills. I possess an analytical mindset; enjoy to observe, research, think and solve problems. I can take care of all the steps from the conception of an idea to the actual finished product. I am proud to have happy customers in my past.

Work experience

In my latest contract, I joined Macmillan Cancer Support to work on Mighty Hikes and Free Wills projects. Mighty Hikes is a high profile event that has grown to be a £5million product in the last 3 years. The purpose of the project was to create a dedicated site and expand the number of events to enable the revenue to grow in excess of £10million per anum within the next 2 years. The site has been a success thus far and is well on track to reaching its goals.

2019 - 2019 Front End Web Developer

(Macmillan Cancer Support) - London, Contract

- HTML5, Sass/Less, CSS3, custom grid
- React, JavaScript
- Azure DevOps, Sourcetree, Gulp/Grunt, Git, InVision

2019 - 2019 Front End Web Developer

(Forward Partners) - London, Contract

- HTML5, Sass, CSS3, Foundation 6
- Various CSS transitions, JavaScript animations
- Webpack, Docker, Git, Figma
- https://forwardpartners.com/
- 2017 2019 Front End Web Developer (Depack)
 - Built React, Bootstrap 4 website
 - Various forms, mobile first design
 - SEO & Email marketing setup
- 2012 2019 Freelance & Contract Jobs

(Websites for individuals and companies)

- Built an e-commerce website with a team of three (first entrepreneurship experience)
- 8+ websites and their maintenance
- Gained and practiced many of his current professional skills

Education

Bilgi University, Istanbul 2013 - 2015Master of Business Administration (MBA)

GPA: 3.80/4.00

Sabanci University, Istanbul 2008 - 2012

Faculty of Engineering and Natural Sciences

B.Sc. Mechatronics Engineering

Hylton High School - Virginia, USA 2007 - 2008 **Exchange Graduation from USA**

Gazi Anatolian High School, Bursa 2003 - 2007

KEY SKILLS

Areas of expertise

JavaScript (6+)

HTML5, CSS3

React (3+)

Sass/Less

jQuery (5+)

Bootstrap 4

PHP (5+)

Foundation 6

MySQL (5+)

REST API

Git (3+)

GitHub

DevTools

Docker

Webpack

Gulp/Grunt

Google Search Console

- Google Analytics
- VSCode, PhpStorm, Notepad++
- Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator
- SolidWorks: 3D solid modelling & Rendering
- Arduino IDE

My Highly detailed portfolio & blog website states out my clear understanding and usage skills of several above-mentioned technologies.

Professional skills

- Detail-oriented, conscious effort to understand causes instead of just the
- Great communication skills for all levels of management.
- Excellent project management and client coordination.
- Ability to work under pressure, self-motivated.
- Able to multitask or focus on single task depending on requirements.
- Strong teamwork skills; communication, collaboration, reliability, leadership, respectfulness.
- UX/UI researcher and advisor.
- Comfortable with server and hosting environments.
- Able to test, detect and debug software problems.
- Superb with hardware and able to fix hardware issues.
- Accurate on deadlines and able to give time estimations.
- Seamless adaptation to new technology and tools.
- Love to research and learn.
- Creative and energetic personality.
- Comfortable with Windows and macOS.
- Fluent English speaker.

Contact details

Ali Tursucular +44 7367 854707 London, UK

alitursucular@gmail.com alitursucular.github.io